# **Punit Shah**

■ punit@punitshah.dev

b punitshah.dev

**™** GitHub: punit-shah

#### **Profile**

Eager and highly motivated software engineer with 3+ years of professional experience. A fast-learner with a logical mind and a keen eye for detail. My objective is to find a suitable position in an environment where I can demonstrate my creativity and genuine enthusiasm, as well as further develop my software development skills.

### **Key Skills**

#### Strong software development skills

- Solid understanding of fundamental programming skills
- In-depth knowledge of modern technologies, including:
  - JavaScript and TypeScript, as well as frameworks such as React
  - HTML5 and CSS3
  - Node.js
  - Microservice-based architectures
  - Cloud-based infrastructure on AWS
- Familiar with modern software engineering practices, such as:
  - Test-driven development and behaviour-driven development
  - Continuous integration and delivery
  - Code review and pair programming

#### Collaborative working

- Experience working in close-knit agile teams
- Can effectively use Git to work collaboratively on projects
- Able to quickly form effective working relationships with colleagues

#### Personal attributes

- Fast-learner eager to learn new skills and able to develop them quickly
- Pays close attention to detail
- Able to make well-thought-out, logical decisions
- Can communicate complex ideas efficiently and accurately

# **Experience**

#### 2019

#### iPlayer Web, BBC

6-month rotation

Worked in a close-knit team with developers and designers to maintain and develop features for the BBC iPlayer website, as well as continually improving the development platform. Was responsible for defining coding standards for CSS & Sass that are now in use by the team.

Became familiar with cutting-edge technologies such as TypeScript, React, Redux, Node.js, NGINX caching, and server-side rendering. Gained a solid understanding of web accessibility and performance issues.

#### 2018 - 2019

#### **Content Production Systems**, BBC

6-month rotation

Worked on a greenfield project to build a next-generation article editor for BBC journalists. Part of a large team with multiple cross-disciplinary sub-teams, all working on the same codebase.

Developed my knowledge of AWS, React, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS, as well as user experience and accessibility concerns.

# News - Data Systems, BBC

6-month rotation

Worked in a team to build a system that can efficiently serve journalism content to numerous outputs around the world.

Gained backend development experience working with Java and Scala in a service-oriented architecture implemented with AWS.

#### 2017 - 2018

#### Platform - iSite. BBC

6-month rotation

Worked as a frontend engineer to maintain and develop features for multiple projects including a content management application and a user-generated content uploader. Helped to build a React component library used by several teams working on internal products.

Was able to quickly pick up and develop new skills in React, Redux, TypeScript, and Sass, as well as hone my existing skills in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

#### 2015 - 2016

# News - Visual Journalism, BBC

13-month placement

First half of placement: Working with journalists and designers to create interactive content for online news stories and specials. Allowed me to broaden my frontend development skills and experiment with lots of tools and technologies.

Second half of placement: Worked in an agile team to develop and maintain a set of tools that allow BBC journalists to create content such as quizzes and charts that are often seen on the BBC News and Sport websites. Gained valuable experience working in a team to deliver software regularly, as well as experience with technologies such as Ember.js, Node.js, PHP, and Cucumber.

## **Education**

#### 2013 - 2017

# **Aberystwyth University**

2:1 BSc (Hons) Computer Science (inc. Integrated Industrial and Professional Training)

#### 2011 - 2013

#### St Dominic's Sixth Form College

A-Levels: Mathematics, Physics, Psychology

AS-Levels: Art & Design

#### 2007 - 2011

# **Park High School**

AS-Levels: ICT

10 GCSEs at grade A to C

#### **Interests**

- A passion for designing and developing for the web
- Volunteering as a coach at Codebar workshops to teach programming skills to underrepresented people
- Going to developer conferences and meetups
- Taking part in hackathons
- Keeping up to date with current affairs

#### References

Available on request.